Good afternoon.
مساء الخير.
My name is Uldus.
إسمي أولدوس.
I am a photo-based artist from Russia.
أنا فنانة فوتوغرافية من روسيا.
I started my way around six years ago
بدأت مشواري منذ 6 سنوات
with ironic self-portraits
بصور شخصية ساخرة
to lay open so many stereotypes
لكشف العديد من الصور النمطية
about nationalities, genders,
عن الجنسيات والأجناس
and social issues —
والقضايا الاجتماعية
["I am Russian. I sell drugs, guns, porno with kids!"] ["Vodka = water. I love vodka!"] (Laughter) —
["أنا روسية. أنا أبيع المخدرات والأسلحة وإباحية الأطفال!"] [". الفودكا هي االماء = أحب الفودكا!"] (ضحك) -
using photography as my tool to send a message. ["Marry me, I need a visa."]
استخدام التصويروسيلتي لإرسال رسالة. ["تزوجني، أحتاج تأشيرة دخول".]
Today, I am still performing in front of the camera
اليوم. ما زلت أؤدي أمام الكاميرا
and trying to be brave like Wonder Woman.
وأحاول أن أكون شجاعة مثل المرأة الخارقة.
I focus on balancing meaningful message,
أركز على إرسال رسائل ذات مغزى،
aesthetic, beauty, composition, some irony, and artifacts.
الجمالية والجمال والإنتاج وبعض السخرية والتحف.
Today, I'm going to tell you about my project,
اليوم سأكلمكم عن مشروعي،
which is named Desperate Romantics.
والذي أسميته الرومانسية البائسة.
They're my artifacts, or paintings
هذه تحفي الفنية أو لوحاتي
from pre-Raphaelites Brotherhood England
مستوحاة من أخوية ما قبل الريفالتيس الإنجليزية
mid-19th century.
منتصف القرن 19.
I took the painting
آخد الرسومات
and gifted new, contemporary meaning
وأعطيها بعدا جديدا ومعنى معاصرا
talking about issues which are surrounding me
يتحدث عن قضايا تحيط بي
in Russia,
في روسيا،
capturing people who are non-models
ملتقطة صورا لأشخاص ليسوا بعارضين
but have an interesting story.
لكن لديهم قصص مثيرة للاهتمام.
This boy is a professional dancer,
هذا الفتى راقص محترف،
only 12 years old,
يبلغ 12 سنة فقط،
but at secondary school, he hides his dancing classes
لكنه في الثانوية ويخفي دروس الرقص،
and is wearing the mask of brutality,
ويرتدي قناعا من العنف،
trying to be united with the rest of his classmates
يحاول أن يبدو متماثلا مع زملاءه
like a storm trooper has no personality.
وكأنه جندي لا شخصية له.
But this boy has goals and dreams
لكن لهذا الولد أهداف وأحلام
but hides it to be socially accepted,
لكن يخاف ألا تكون مقبولة في مجتمعه،
because being different isn't easy,
فأن تكون مختلفا ليس سهلا،
especially in Russia.
خصوصا في روسيا.
Next portrait interpretation is metaphoric.
العمل القادم هو عمل مجازي.
And this is Nikita,
وهذا هو نكيتا
a security guard from one of the bars
حارس أمن من إحدى الحانات
in St. Petersburg.
في سانت بترسبرغ.
He likes to say, "You wouldn't like me when I'm angry,"
يحب أن يقول، "لن تحبيني عندما أكون غاضبا"
quoting Hulk from the movie,
نقلا عن فيلم هالك،
but I've never seen him angry.
لكنني لم أره قط غاضبا.
He hides his sensitivities and romantic side,
يخفي أحاسيسه وجانيه الرومانسي،
because in Russia, among guys,
لأنه في روسيا، عند الرجال،
that's not cool to be romantic,
ليس جيدا أن أن تبدو رومانسيا،
but it's cool to be surrounded with women
لكنه من الجيد أن تحاط بالنساء
and look like an aggressive hulk.
وتبدو مثل هالك العنيف.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
Sometimes, in my project,
أحيانا في أعمالي،
I would take the painting
آخد اللوحة
and give it new meaning
وأعطيها معنى جديد
and new temptation about it.
وتجربة جديدة حول موضوعها.
Sometimes, I would compare facial features
أحيانا، أود مقارنة ملامح الوجه
and playing with words:
واللعب بالكلمات:
irony, Iron Man, ironing man.
السخرية، الرجل الحديدي، رجل يكوي.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
Through the artifacts,
عن طريق اللوحات الفنية،
I bring social issues
أنقل القضايا الاجتماعية
which surround me in Russia into the conversation.
التي تحيط بي في روسيا إلى هاته المحادثة.
Interesting fact about marriage in Russia,
حقيقة مثيرة للاهتمام حول الزواج في روسيا،
that most of the 18, 19-year-old girls
أن معظم الفتيات البالغات 18 و19 عاما
are already ready, and dream to get married.
هن جاهزات ويحلمن بالزواج
We're taught from childhood,
ندرّس منذ الطفولة،
successful marriage means successful life,
بأن الزواج الناجح يعني حياة ناجحة،
so most of the girls kind of fight
لذلك فمعظم الفتيات يقاتلن
to get a good husband.
للحصول على زوج جيد.
And what about me?
وماذا عني؟
I'm 27 years old.
عمري 27 سنة.
For Russian society, I'm an old maid
بالنسبة للمجتمع الروسي أنا خادمة قديمة
and hopeless to ever get married.
وميئوس جدا من زواجها.
That's why you see me in a Mexican fighter mask,
لهذا السبب تراني في قناع مقاتل مكسيكي،
in the wedding dress, all desperate in my garden.
بفستان الزفاف، يائسة في حديقتي.
But remember, irony is the key,
ولكن تذكروا، السخرية هي المفتاح،
and this is actually to motivate girls
وهذا في الواقع لتحفيز الفتيات
to fight for goals, for dreams,
للقتال من أجل أهدافهن وأحلامهن،
and change stereotypes.
وتغيير تلك الصور النمطية.
Be brave. Be ironic — it helps.
كن شجاعا وكن ساخرا- هذا يساعد-
Be funny and create some magic.
كن مرحا واخلق بعض السحر.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)